Andrew Schell Andrewscience 304@gmail.com - 425-463-5034

DATA MODELING | SQL ANALYTICS | TABLEAU DASHBOARDS

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Data Management: Data cleaning, database analysis, data quality assessment, pattern identification, visualization of data insights, skilled at data process automation, DevOps, data documentation, and statistical analysis

Research: Data science research methods, data mining, SQL database, engineered problem-solving data analysis with Python – prototyping/tool building; bench science experience Markov Hidden Method and Monte Carlo for analysis.

Communication/Team Skills/Professional Practice: Highly developed interpersonal/communication skills; Proven team collaborator and independent contributor to raising team productivity with critical thinking and attention to detail

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Lead (stealth) – Recruiterless.ai, Seattle, WA

July 2021 – Dec 2022

- Wrote Python backend to automate 62% of the recruiting process with 91.8% resume data accuracy with BERT NLP
- Optimized AWS pipeline, saving the company \$146,000, and managed a team of five with weekly virtual standups.
- Developed \$116M in five new revenue channels based on interview data with 23 HrTech CEOs

Data Science Analyst (contract) – Your Data Talking, Seattle, WA

Oct 2014 – July 2021

- Created data ETL pipeline to automate SQL cleaning and wrote HR analytics that reduced employee turnover by 44%.
- Rewrote backend analytics system to automate Google Analytics, saving 9 hours a week of data preparation.

Archive Assistant, Secretary of State – Washington State Historical Archives, Seattle, WA Sep 2019 – June 2020

- Improved archivist output with more efficient document research and retrieval as a student intern
- I researched computer vision and NLP architecture to digitize historical documents for online access.

Data Analyst (contract) - Lifespan Bioscience, Seattle, WA

Sept 2017 - Mar 2018

- Wrote backend script to reduce weekly software update merge time by 400% with pytest and version control
- Lead Machine Learning team to sort and classify gene expressions by segmenting system design tasks
- Rewrote clustering algorithm to 91% accuracy via Supervised Learning based on NCBI and SQL server database.
- Engineered ML pipeline for ELISA, Immunoassay, Protein, BioChemical, mono and polyclonal antibody research

Salesforce Admin/Developer (contract) – Presbyterian Senior Services, New York, NY

Jan 2015 - March 2017

- Migrated 10,000+ HIPPA records from Access data into Salesforce using unit test pytest via Python, saving \$63,000
- Improved patient onboarding speed by 148% with a redesigned Salesforce interface to align with HIPAA and Nursing staff

Data Analyst (contract) - SPROXIL, Boston, MA

Sept 2015 - June 2016

- Analyzed customer time series buying patterns, leading to a 312% increase in website engagement
- Wrote an automated SQL script to reduce errors of attribution by 41% for Google Analytics data
- Rectified gender attribution errors in Google Analytics and SQL database, saving 71% of marketing waste

Financial Advisor - Country Financial – Bellevue, WA

Oct 2007 - May 2014

- Improved sales "call to close" ratio by 262.5% with Reinforcement learning and multivariate underwriting risk model.
- Reduced client churn by 38% and improved Net Promoter Score by 188% from 3.9 to 8.1 on 482 B2B/B2C client accounts.

Volunteer, Puget Sound Python Users Group – Seattle PuPPy, Galvanize, Seattle, WA

Mar 2015 – Oct 2023

Mentor new college grads and others on best practices of programming analytics as a data science mentor.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science Data Analytics, Bellevue College, Bellevue, WA

Sept 2020 - Dec 2022

- Hypothesis testing, data sourcing, cleaning, statistical analysis, analytical dashboards, visualizations, and databases
 Stanford School of Engineering, Stanford Online Edx SQL Certification
 June 2023 Dec 2024
- SQL Indexes and Transactions, Constraints and Triggers, Views and Authorization for data cleaning, ETL and analytics